racedepartment.com 2019-04-07

# Privacy Policy | RaceDepartment - Latest Formula 1, Motorsport, and Sim Racing News

  * Welcome to the largest (sim) racing website in the world!

Blurring the line between real and virtual motorsports. 
  * 

We are RaceDepartment.com operated by Department Network ("we", "our", "us"). We’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. If you have questions about your personal information please contact us.

## What information we hold about you

The type of data that we collect and process includes:

  * Your name or username.
  * Your email address.
  * Your IP address.
  * Information related to any financial transactions which may be carried out.
  * Information related to the use of our dedicated gaming servers.
  * Basic profile information from third party services you link to your account (eg. Facebook, Twitter, Steam).

Further data may be collected if you choose to share it, such as if you fill out fields on your profile.

We collect some or all of this information in the following cases:

  * You register as a member on this site.
  * You fill out our contact form.
  * You browse this site. See "Cookie policy" below.
  * You fill out fields on your profile.
  * You purchase a premium membership
  * You play games on our dedicated servers
  * You connect to our voice communications platforms such as Teamspeak
  * You purchase goods or services on this site.

## How your personal information is used

We may use your personal information in the following ways:

  * For the purposes of making you a registered member of our site, in order for you to contribute content to this site.
  * We may use your email address to inform you of activity on our site.
  * Your IP address is recorded when you perform certain actions on our site. Your IP address is never publicly visible.
  * To promote, publish news, standings, and statistics related to our gaming and racing events.
  * To fight spam, fraud, and other abuse of services.
  * To fulfill lawful recording requirements for example finanacial business accounting and tax records.
  * To determine if/when to serve advertisements.

## Other ways we may use your personal information.

In addition to notifying you of activity on our site which may be relevant to you, from time to time we may wish to communicate with all members any important information such as newsletters or announcements by email. You can opt-in to or opt-out of such emails in your profile.

We may collect non-personally identifiable information about you in the course of your interaction with our site. This information may include technical information about the browser or type of device you're using. This information will be used purely for the purposes of analytics and tracking the number of visitors to our site.

## Potential consequences of processing

By creating an account on our sites or any of their related services you may make personal data about yourself public and accessible to others on your profile or through interactions such as replying to or creating forum posts. This may in some cases constitute special category protected data which is considered manifestly made public by the user.

Due to the public nature of information posted on our sites and services it may be possible for third parties to derive identifying personal data from posts by reading, inference, supplemental research, or automated extraction and analysis. You may also choose to use the service without posting data or engaging in network interactions. However, if you do not agree with and accept the risks of such usage, you may not use the services. You are free to use your real name or pseudonym of your choosing as your username. You may request your username be changed to a pseudonym at any time if your current username contains personally identifying information by using the contact us form.

Some game services are hosted wholly or in part by the games developer/publisher or other third party. Due to this some information about you or your game session is exposed and possibly collected by those parties.

## Keeping your data secure

We are committed to ensuring that any information you provide to us is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable measures and procedures to safeguard and secure the information that we collect.

We use encryption (HTTPS/TLS) to protect data transmitted to and from our site. However, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure, so we can’t guarantee security. You use the Service at your own risk, and you’re responsible for taking reasonable measures to secure your account.

The data transfer mechanism used by game clients and the servers they connect to is entirely at the discretion of the developers of the software. Users should note that communications within game software may not be encryped during transmission and that this is beyond our control and liability.

## Embedded Content

Posts, comments, and messages on our sites and services may contain third-party embeds, which may in some cases collect and store personal data. The use of personal data by embedded content providers is not covered by this statement, but by the privacy policies of those sites or services.

## Cookie policy

Cookies are small text files which are set by us on your computer which allow us to provide certain functionality on our site, such as being able to log in, or remembering certain preferences.

We have a detailed cookie policy and more information about the cookies that we set on [this page](https://www.racedepartment.com/help/cookies).

## Payment Processors

We provide some services in conjunction with external payment processors. Those companies acting as payment processors may collect and store personal data related to your billing information and history in order to provide their services, and may collect and store personal data and business data to prevent fraud and other abuse or as required by by law for tax and accounting purposes. Wehn you perform transactions on this site you agree that you have read, understood, and agree to the privacy policy of the processor you choose at checkout.

Our current payment processors are:

  * [PayPal](https://paypal.com/) \- [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/gi/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)

## Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies who serve ads to help keep content free. For these partners, we put additional restrictions on how your data can be used to prevent it from misuse. For instance, we do not allow these partners to take your information for profiling and personalising ads on other sites.

You may review the following for a full list of partners and purposes: 

## Rights

You have a right to access the personal data we hold about you or obtain a copy of it. To do so please contact us. If you believe that the information we hold for you is incomplete or inaccurate, you may contact us to ask us to complete or correct that information.

You also have the right to request the erasure of your personal data. Please contact us if you would like us to remove your personal data. The removal process will not remove your public facing content such as forum posts and comments. This data will be anonymised and no longer linked to you personal information. After removal some of your combined account data may continue to exist in backups for a period of 90 days. Some single data points such as your IP may continue to reside in logs for up to 1 year.

If there are posts or other content on the site which contain personally identifying information you wish to remove, please click the 'report' button under the post and provide an explanation of the nature of the information.

If some of your personal information such as an IP address or email is in use to implement limitations or restrictions to access services, for example a ban from the site we may continue to use this data under our legitimate interest to keep our services safe, secure, free of spam, and free of abuse.

## Acceptance of this policy

Continued use of our site signifies your acceptance of this policy. If you do not accept the policy then please do not use this site. When registering we will further request your explicit acceptance of the privacy policy.

## Changes to this policy

We may make changes to this policy at any time. You may be asked to review and re-accept the information in this policy if it changes in the future.

**This policy was last updated: 26th May 2018**

  1. This site uses cookies to help personalise content, tailor your experience and to keep you logged in if you register.  
By continuing to use this site, you are consenting to our use of cookies. 

__
